A Guide to the Woman’s Club of McLean Papers, 1994-2017
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Woman’s Club of McLean Papers, 1994-2017
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-55
.5 linear feet
The Woman’s Club of McLean Papers consists of .5 linear feet and spans the years 1994-2017 and contains newsletters, programs, brochures, lists, and ticket books.
Woman’s Club of McLean
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Items donated July 7, 2015 by the Woman’s Club of McLean through Kathlyn Burnell and Mildred Thompson. Additions donated on February 23, 2018 by Kathlyn Burnell.
Historical and Biographical Information
On February 4, 1958, eighteen women interested in organizing a woman’s club met at the home of Mrs. C. Crowell Squire in McLean, Virginia. The club installed Squire as its first President on March 11, 1958 and the group became a member of the General Federation of Women’s Clubs (GFWC) on April 18, 1958.
Throughout its existence, the club has provided service to the McLean community through volunteer activities and financial support. Their biggest event is an annual Holiday Homes Tour and Boutique held each December. The club has published cook books, hosted fashion and talent shows, supported and financially contributed to the development of the McLean Community Center, granted scholarships to local high school students, and sponsored various other fundraising events and community projects.
Scope and Content
The Woman’s Club of McLean Papers consists of .5 linear feet and spans the years 1994-2017 and contains newsletters, programs, brochures, lists, and ticket books. Subjects include the annual Holiday Homes Tour and general history of the club.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
Index Terms
McLean (Va.) - History; Woman’s Club of McLean (Mclean, Va.)
Container List
- List, Woman’s Club of McLean Past Presidents, Honorary Chairmen, and Home Tours, 2015, 2017
- General Federation of Women’s Clubs of Virginia: A Brief History, 2014
- Brochures, Undated
- Ticket Books, Holiday Homes Tour, 1975, 1981, 1983-1984
- Ticket Books, Holiday Homes Tour, 1988-1997
- Ticket Books, Holiday Homes Tour, 1999-2006
- Ticket Books, Holiday Homes Tour, 2007-2014
- Ticket Books, Holiday Homes Tour, 2015-2017
- Program, Kitchen and Garden Tour, 2013
- Newsletters, “The McLean Woman”, 2011, 2015
- Booklet, “The Woman’s Club of McLean 40th Anniversary, 1958-1998”, 1998
- Booklet, “The Woman’s Club of McLean 50 Years of Community Service 1958-2008”, 2008